Finding Aid for the Synanon Foundation Records LSC.0342
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Films
  - NBC - Synanon's 10th Anniversary: Composite Reversal Print, 1968; yrlsc_342_723_003; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:09:43) 350 feet; Emulsion tacky during unwinding and slightly sticking to itself. Color slightly faded, but mostly all still there. Uncut film. Faint images of Chuck Dederich in clear film tail run-out. (Box 723, Case 3)
    Side of can labeled: "H 28/2 NBC 10 Year Anniversary" Synanon Films label on lid: "Title: NBC - Synanon's 10th Anniversary No.: H27-2 / Property of: Synanon Foundation, Inc. / Running time: 7:36 min / Feet: 274' / Color" Other labels on lid include: "Also referred to as INTERVIEW AT OCEAN FRONT #1" and "Tape 1 / print / Synanon / Film no. H27 / #61 / 8-08-80" Note inside can identifies contents as "H-27 SYNANON - ITS TENTH YEAR, NBC-TV, 10-9-68, color, 7:36 min. Tom Brokaw narrates / 1910 Ocean Front, various scenes: "stew [game], kitchen, service [gas] station, school, art workshop, hoopla. [...] and [...] talk; about 1/3 of film is an interview with CED [Chuck Dederich] which he begins with: 'We have had the beginnings of a university - in quality - for a long time.'" Later generation copy of yrlsc_342_723_002, but uncut and with fewer scratches. Color quality less good in this copy.
  - Dance Footage 1962: Negative, yrlsc_342_723_004; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:03:28) 125 feet; Some slightly rough edges, but no torn perfs. Occasional notches in edges likely made for negative matching. Uncut film. (Box 723, Case 4)
    Synanon archive #102. Metal can labeled: "#11 Dance Footage 1962 Negative." Head leader: "Do not project - Camera Original - Negative - #11 Dance Footage 1962 - Head" and "21404B The Synanon HD." Tail leader labeled: "Foot The Synanon 21404B" People dancing on a stage in harsh lighting (creating big shadows behind them). Some in animal print clothes. Others drumming.
  - Synanon at 1351: Print, circa 1962; yrlsc_342_723_005; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:04:51) 175 feet; Torn perforations throughout. Film curling in on itself. (Box 723, Case 5)
    Palmer Film Services label on can: "Title: Synanon at 1351 - 1962 or '63. Footage of beach, diningroom, game and Band / Silent / Running time: 3:00 / Black and white silent" Second label: "Orig # H5 / Audit + Visual #28 / Print / Title: Footage of beach, dining room, game - 1352" Side of can labeled: "H5 Synanon on 1351" Synanon Department of Films green "Protect-a-Print" leader at head, followed by clear film labeled: "Jazz Scene U.S.A." Printed-in handwriting at tail: "A Roll - Foot - Synanon Documentary" and red "Do not rewind" leader at tail. 1351 Ocean Front, Santa Monica, was address of National Guard armory building that Synanon took over. Shots of Synanon House sign. Chuck Dederich and others sitting around table inside. Close-ups on signboards with job assignments. Band playing music at end. Appears to have been edited into "Jazz Scene USA - Sounds of Synanon" (yrlsc_342_587_005), with music score performed by the Sounds of Synanon band in that program.
  - Cardroom Kayex: Camera Original Outtakes, circa 1971-1972; yrlsc_342_723_006; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:04:10) 150 feet; Small segments of film previously loosely taped together. Now spliced together with leader slugs in between. Tape splices for mag stripe only made on non-mag side. Reel starts with 1971 TXR mag stripe film and switches to double perf silent 1972 PXR approximately halfway through reel. Persistent base scratch throughout reel. (Box 723, Case 6)
    Synanon archive #253. In metal can with likely erroneous (reused) label: "From Synanon / [...] / To Consolidated Film Industries / Title: Wedding / Prod # D-6 / Film type: 7242 / Roll # ARRI 400' / Date: 8/7 / Develop normal" Head leader labeled: "A26 Cardroom Kayex - Synanon - Head PFH" Men in military uniform rowing boats with children on a sunny day in urban environment. Appears to be on Lake Merritt in Oakland. Close-ups on faces while rowing. Children on dock at lake. Synanon branded kayaks.
  - Industries Move: Camera Original Outtakes, 1972; yrlsc_342_723_007; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:10:25) 375 feet; Small segments of film previously loosely taped together. Now spliced together with leader slugs in between. Original head leader disconnected from film and now spliced together. Redox blemishes from original tape throughout. Warping worse at head. Mix of double perf (Kodak) and single perf (Agfa) - all silent. Emulsion scratching more frequent than base. (Box 723, Case 7)
    Synanon archive #254. Side of can labeled: "A-9 - Industries Move - Orig. - Outs - Pic - 1972" May depict moving Synanon Industries from Southern California to Oakland/Bay Area. Signs in film include: "Welcome to Synanon Oakland - Movie Capital of the Foundation" and "Welcome - We Like Industries :)" and "Welcome to Oakland, Industries, Yeah!!" Synanon Club awning in Oakland. Loading furniture into building. Synanon Industries letterhead in typewriter. "Synanon Industries Wants You!!" recruitment poster. Chalkboard office floorplan. Synanon water tower in San Francisco.
  - Mobile Dental Unit: Work Print Outtakes, 1972; yrlsc_342_723_008; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:09:18) 335 feet; Separate segments of film either previously taped loosely together or wrapped without tape. Now spliced together with leader slug in between. Printed-through stock information: Kodak TXR Safety Film, 1972. Redox blemishes from original tape. Some torn perforations throughout. Film is warping and curling from tight wind. All tape splices were added, any cement splices are original. (Box 723, Case 8)
    Synanon archive #255a-f. Inside can labeled: "A-35 - Mobil Dental Unit - W.P. - Outs - Pic - 1972" University of Southern California Mobile Dental Clinic. Dentistry in action. Chuck Dederich observes the scene. Might include dentistry on piglets as well.
  - Synanon on Film - June 1972: Composite Reversal Print, yrlsc_342_723_009; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:11:06) 400 feet; Uncut film. (Box 723, Case 9)
    Plastic can with Palmer Film Services label: "Title: #6 Synanon on Film - June 1972 / Property of: Synanon Foundation Inc. / [...] / Running time: 10 min / Feet: 387' / Black and White" Also labeled: "No 11 - Synanon on Film (#6)" on lid. Bottom of can labeled: "JUNE / 'Upward Mobility' / 'Getting the News Past Fresno' / 'T.B. Tanker'" Three news stories: "Upward Mobility"; "Getting the News Past Fresno" including "Welcome back Chuck and Betty" party/reception, a recorded Game session with shots of Sony TC-106A tape recorder, office with sign "The Game: Synanon's Government"; and last story "Tanker (Tomales Bay)" featuring Synanon Fire Department truck driving from city to Tomales Bay ranch. End credit: "Synanon on Film - an Oakland Movie Lot production"
  - Cardboard Act as if - W.P. - Outtakes, 1972; yrlsc_342_723_010; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:04:10) 150 feet; Large number of short segments previously loosely taped together. (Box 723, Case 10)
    Synanon archive #246. Side of can labeled: "A-28 - Cardboard Act as if - W.P. - Outtakes - Pic 72 -" Adult men in uniform with children on boats on urban water (likely Lake Merritt in Oakland). Probably related to yrlsc_342_723_006.
  - Egg Eating: Camera Original Outtakes, 1972; yrlsc_342_723_011; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:03:28) 125 feet; First third of reel consists of segments original found loosely taped together with crumbling and dusty tape. These were spliced together with tape. Remainder of reel consists of original cement splices, some of which were reinforced with splice tape. (Box 723, Case 11)
    Synanon archive #248. Can with Palmer Film Services label: "Title: A9 - O - Out - Pic - 1972 / Running time: 4:40" Side of can labeled: "A-3 - Egg Eating - Orig. Outs - Pic - 1972" Sign identifies "Great Scrambled Egg Eating Contest" with weigh-in on October 6 and context on Octover 7 in "the Lot." Men sitting at table eating while spectators watch. People cheering with "Right on Rocky" and "Scarfin' Rocky" signs. Rocky likely one of the egg eaters depicted. May start with Pledge of Allegiance recitation. Many out of focus shots.
- Founder's office chron, 1978-1980
  - Founder's office chrons - through Founder's office chron -, December 1977 June 1978. (Box 519)
  - Founder's office chron-July through Founder's office chron -, June 1980. (Box 520)
  - Founder's office chrons - through CED chrons -, July 1980 January 1988. (Box 521)
- Interviews - Transcripts
  - Love & marriage through Religion-, July 1979. (Box 116)
  - Transcript - SFVSC lecture #1 - curtain raiser - through BD Digest., September 1968 (Box 117)
- Literature
  - Where junkies learn to hang tough (New York Times magazine - ) through Scrapbook (2 of 2)., 1965 (Box 324)
  - Addict heal thyself through Synanon looks to the future. (Box 117)
  - Synanon offers new lifestyle through Proverbs, slogans & folk sayings in the therapeutic community. (Box 118)
  - The school - an overview through Bay Guardian -, October 1975. (Box 119)
  - The Beam - Michigan Prison - through Synanon: Breaking the chains., January 1976 (Box 120)
  - Report of assembly intermediary committee on criminal procedure through Synanon the movie. (Box 121)
  - Combat liberalism through Daytop village. (Box 122)
  - Dederich, Betty - biographical material through Durham Morning Post (Box 123)
  - East Ridge - The way out through Emerson - The Oversoul. (Box 124)
  - Emerson - Power through Enright, John B. (Box 125)
  - Enright, John B - A balanced view of Synanon through Ferderber, Skip - Synanon versus the Examiner. (Box 126)
  - Film festival through Fuller - Vertical is to live.... (Box 127)
  - Fuller - The child & environment - through Garfield, Howard - The Synanon religion., 1966 (Box 128)
  - Assumptions of the Synanon game through Garrett, Glenda - The bridge. (Box 129)
  - Germany House - News from Synanon through Harrison, Bill - The trip. (Box 130)
  - Harrison, Bill - The Synanon road toward... through Instant guide -, 1974. (Box 131)
  - Instant guide - through Journal of drug issues., 1978 (Box 132)
  - Judicial Highlights - through La pagina del fundador., March 1979 (Box 133)
  - Los Angeles Times Home Magazine - through Los Angeles Times West., 1966 (Box 134)
  - Learning - Education in the land of Mao through Leubel, Kathy - Kathy Lewbel on McCarthyism -, December 1977. (Box 135)
  - Life - Synanon through Long Island Press -, March 1964. (Box 136)
  - Look articles through Los Angeles Free Press -, April 1976. (Box 137)
  - Los Angeles Free Press - Life inside Synanon - through Man's Magazine -, 1972 1962. (Box 138)
  - Manas - through Maslow, Abe., June 1956 (Box 139)
  - Maslow - Self-actualizing people through MD Medical News magazine -, April 1968. (Box 140)
  - Men's Stylist through New York Times Magazine. (Box 141)
  - New York Times Magazine - through Oakland Tribune Magazine -, May 1965 September 1973. (Box 142)
  - Ofshe, Richard through Pacific Sun -, April 1980. (Box 143)
  - Pageant through Patton, Tom - Synanon philosophy. (Box 144)
  - People Magazine - through Punk squad thank you cards., March 1975 (Box 145)
  - QED Renaissance - through Russian Heights, Pacific Hill Gazette -, October 1970 April 1964. (Box 146)
  - Rehak, Frank J through Synanon libel suit versus Time -, 1978. (Box 147)
  - The school - A Synanon function through Seven voices from Synanon. (Box 148)
  - SFVSC - sociology workshop through Southland Sunday -, August 1974. (Box 149)
  - So you want to play the game? through Synanon Foundation by CED -, October 1958. (Box 150)
  - Simon, Steve - the Synanon game - a lecture through Synanon - Nevada State Prison. (Box 151)
  - Synanon News - through Synanon Story -, 1963 October 1977. (Box 152)
  - Synanon Story - through Synanon Story -, December 1977 October 1980. (Box 153)
- Microfilm
  CONTAINS UNPROCESSED MICROFILM] MATERIALS: Special equipment will be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - Various legal cases [For index - see box 551] Approximately 90 reels [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 513)
  - Various legal cases; Approximately 60 reels [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 514)
- Miscellaneous
  - Office pictures; 8 items, mounted, relating to events in Synanon's history [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 432)
- Miscellaneous Newspaper Articles
  - Synanon San Diego battles - through Literature 15., 1967 (Box 179)
  - Literature 14 through Detroit. (Box 180)
  - El Cajon through Articles -, November 1978. (Box 181)
  - Articles - through Articles -, December 1978 1959. (Box 182)
  - Historical subject files through Clippings -, 1973-1979. (Box 183)
  - Articles - (2 of 2) through Clippings - (2 of 2)., ca. 1973-1979 ca. 1973-1979 (Box 184)
- Negatives
  - B061 through B075. (Box 321)
  - B001 through B313. (Box 321)
  - 001 through 021. (Box 321)
  - B11 through J045 Includes - B12-B20, F011-F233, G001-G281, H001-H230, I001-I155. (Box 322)
- Notebooks
  - The best meals in town through seven voices. (Box 552)
  - The Synanon game through People business primer fellowship notebook - Curtis and Irene Marshall -, 1982. (Box 553)
  - Betty had a style through Betty D. writers' conference - original - vol.1. (Box 554)
  - Betty D. writers' conference - copy - vol.2 through Newcomer department. (Box 555)
  - Mini fellowship summaries - vol.1 (folder 1 of 2) through Chuck Dederich holds court. (Box 556)
  - Dissipation class lectures - examiner case (folder 1 of 2) through Synanon religious material. (Box 557)
  - Reports to patrons on the accomplishments of the Charles E. Dederich collected works project through Education notebook. (Box 558)
  - Thickened light college through Synanon history miscellaneous. (Box 559)
  - Summing up notebook - number 1 through CED: transcripts - religion - book 2. (Box 560)
  - Home Place press conference through Bald head celebration -, 1981. (Box 561)
  - Synanon trip - May 23-25 - Yvette Van Dalsem through minutes. (Box 562)
  - Synanon research notebook through Synanon miscellaneous. (Box 563)
  - Miscellaneous transcripts through Synanon religion notes. (Box 564)
  - Not at this table and other miscellaneous transcripts through Synanon School - notes, papers, observations -, 1971. (Box 565)
  - Unicept through College courser - - Michele Albano., 1974 (Box 566)
  - Synanon literature miscellaneous through Source notebook - Emerson, Fuller, McLuhan. (Box 567)
- Office of Education
  - Testing correspondence - through - Testing materials and instructions., 1972-1973 1975 (Box 410)
  - Testing correspondence - through - Synanon School cognitive and achievement evaluation., 1975 1976 (Box 411)
  - Scoring reports through Testing instructions and materials -, 1976. (Box 412)
- People Files
  - Synanon: the people business - scrapbook copy - pp.55-58 missing. (Box 59)
  - Alman, Debbie through Bloomfield, Henri. (Box 153)
  - Bullis, Dick through Cooper, Milton. (Box 154)
  - Cooper, M. - miscellaneous literature through Chairman's office -, 1967-1969. (Box 155)
  - CED profile through Miscellaneous correspondence -, 1976. (Box 156)
  - Synanon design reports - through Saga of Synanon., 1975 (Box 157)
  - Endore, Guy - conferences - through Endore, Guy - manuscript - It will emerge., 1967-1968 (Box 158)
  - Endore, Guy - Saga of Synanon - manuscript (revised) through Endore, Guy - Saga of Synanon - manuscript (revised). (Box 159)
  - Endore, Guy - Saga of Synanon - manuscript (revised) through Endore, Guy - Saga of Synanon - manuscript (original). (Box 160)
  - Endore, Guy - Saga of Synanon - parts 1 & 2 through Endore, Guy - The nearest thing to heaven. (Box 161)
  - Endore, Guy - Saga of Synanon through Endore, Guy - It will emerge. (Box 162)
  - Endore, Guy - Saga of Synanon - series 4 through Endore, Guy - Saga of Synanon - series 6. (Box 163)
  - Endore, Guy - Saga of Synanon - series 7 through Hamer, Charlie - biography. (Box 164)
  - Files index through Mud files. (Box 165)
  - Music through Speeches to ADGAP women. (Box 166)
  - Synanon literature through Miscellaneous to regents, directors, etc. -, 1967-1970. (Box 167)
  - To Jack Hurst - through Healdsburg., 1965-1972 (Box 168)
  - R. Kennedy through Reid Kimball - chronology file -, 1968-1970. (Box 169)
  - Kimball, Reid - listing of audio tapes through Snapshots. (Box 170)
  - Kimball, Reid - photos through Kimball, Reid - sympathy letters. (Box 171)
  - King, Martin Luther through Maslow, Abe. (Box 172)
  - Maslow, Wally through Patton, Tom. (Box 173)
  - Pratte, Jesse through Stern, Chester. (Box 174)
  - Sorkin, Dan - group 2, file 1 - biography through Yablonsky, Lewis (2 of 3). (Box 175)
  - Yablonski, Lewis (3 of 3) through Young, Bob. (Box 176)
  - Kimball, Reid - personal effects (1 of 2) through Miscellaneous material. (Box 325)
- Photos & Negatives
  - Loose photos; [OVERSIZE BOX] #1. (Box 427)
  - Airplanes - air strip - buses - fire truck through S. (Box 428)
  - San Francisco Seawall - paint factory through Loose photos (2 folders) [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 429)
  - Loose photos (folder 3) through Loose photos (folder 6). (Box 430)
  - Loose photos; [OVERSIZE BOX] #2. (Box 431)
  - 1141 through 1275 missing - 1142, 1146, 1154-1160, 1165, 1166, 1173-1175, 1178, 1183- 1184, 1187-1188, 1190-1191, 1193, 1195, 1198, 1201, 1203, 1206, 1208-1209, 1222, 1224, 1229-1230, 1235, 1237-1240, 1245, 1250-1251, 1254-1258, 1260, 1268, 1270, 1272-1273. (Box 281)
  - Folder contents begin with 1276 through 1379 missing - 1288, 1291-1292, 1298, 1304. 1311-1312, 1318-1320, 1327, 1331-1334, 1345, 1347, 1362, 1375, 1377-1378 (Box 282)
  - Folder contents begin with 1380 through 1480 missing - 1391, 1398, 1400, 1402, 1404, 1408, 1412-1413, 1416-1417, 1419-1420, 1426, 1428, 1433, 1440. (Box 283)
  - Folder contents begin with 1481 through 1569. (Box 284)
  - Folder contents begin with 1570 through 1655. (Box 285)
  - Folder contents begin with 1656 through 1736 missing - 1724, 1731-1733. (Box 286)
  - Folder contents begin with 1778 through 2087 missing - 1779, 2049. (Box 287)
  - Folder contents begin with 2088 through 3035 missing - 2124-2125, 2129-3000. (Box 288)
  - Folder contents begin with 3036 through 3109. (Box 289)
  - Folder contents begin with 3110 through 3189. (Box 290)
  - Folder contents begin with 3190 through 3272. (Box 291)
  - Folder contents begin with 3273 through 3368. (Box 292)
  - Folder contents begin with 3571 through 5029 missing - 3571, 3750, 4001-4026, 4029-4034, 4036-4039, 4208, 4502-4516, 4518-4520, 4524, 4526-4531, 5001-5025, 5027-5029. (Box 293)
  - 5030 through 5118. (Box 294)
  - Folder contents begin with 5119 through 5207 missing - 5175. (Box 295)
  - Folder contents begin with 5208 through 5294. (Box 296)
  - Folder contents begin with 5295 through 5375 missing - 5361. (Box 297)
  - Folder contents begin with 5376 through 5454. (Box 298)
  - Folder contents begin with 5455 through 5539 missing - 5472. (Box 299)
  - Folder contents begin with 5540 through 5634 2 of 5590 - missing - 5577, 5627, 5630. (Box 300)
  - Folder contents begin with 5635 through 5709 2 of 5695 - missing - 5650. (Box 301)
  - Folder contents begin with 5710 through 5799 missing - 5725, 5752, 5757, 5759, 5764, 5793. (Box 302)
  - Folder contents begin with 5800 through 5885 missing - 5803, 5805, 5818, 5826, 5837-5849. (Box 303)
  - Folder contents begin with 7000 through 8054 2 of 8029, 2 of 8034 - missing - 7041 - 7999, 8010, 8026, 8032, 8042-8043. (Box 304)
  - Folder contents begin with 8055 through 8154 missing - 8136. (Box 305)
  - Folder contents begin with 8155 through 8249 2 of 8195 - missing - 8211, 8217. (Box 306)
  - Folder contents begin with 8250 through 10,067 missing - 8262, 8270-8271, 8275-8999, 9006-9999, 10,006-10,007, 10,029, 10,034. (Box 307)
  - Folder contents begin with 12000 through 13020 missing - 12004, 12033, 12037, 12059-13002, 13004, 13014, 13019. (Box 308)
  - Folder contents begin with 13021 through 13100 2 of 13067 - missing - 13024, 13028, 13030, 13032, 13034-13035, 13044, 13047, 13050-13052, 13057, 13071, 13080, 13090, 13093-13094. (Box 309)
  - Folder contents begin with 13102 through 13138 missing - 13109, 13117, 13119, 13122, 13125, 13127, 13129-13130. (Box 310)
  - Folder contents begin with 13052 through 16004 2 of 13153 - missing - 13142, 13144, 13146, 13148, 13154-13155, 13158, 13166, 13168, 13171-13175, 13177, 13180, 13183, 13189-14000, 14004-14005, 14007-16000. (Box 311)
  - Folder contents begin with Loose photos #1 through Loose photos #4., 1963-1966 (Box 508)
  - Folder contents begin with Loose photos #5 through Loose photos #2., 1963-1966 1971-1975 (Box 509)
  - Folder contents begin with Loose photos #3 through Loose photos #7., 1971-1975 1971-1975 (Box 510)
  - Folder contents begin with Loose photos 1971-1975 #8 through Loose photos, 1977-present. (Box 511)
  - Othersize loose photos 1958-1962 through Oversize loose photos [OVERSIZE BOX]., 1977-present (Box 512)
  - 01 through 09. (Box 312)
  - 10 through 16. (Box 313)
  - 17 through 24. (Box 314)
  - 25 through 30. (Box 315)
  - 31 through 39. (Box 316)
  - 40 through 43. (Box 317)
  - 44 through 47. (Box 318)
  - 48 through 53. (Box 319)
- Press Releases 1972-1976
  - Undated through September 1973. (Box 112)
  - November 1973 through April 1974. (Box 113)
  - May 1974 through November 1974. (Box 114)
  - December 1974 through 1976 miscellaneous. (Box 115)
- Saga of Synanon
  - Saga of Synanon (bound copy) through Confidential magazine, (August 1961). (Box 413)
  - Scapbook through Bill Crawford The Trip, Life mags. - [OVERSIZE] (Box 414)
  - Saga of Synanon through Jady Dederich's academy notebooks (folders 1 and 2 of 3). (Box 415)
  - Jady Dederich's academy notebooks (folder 3 of 3). (Box 416)
- School Babies - Adult Portraits
  - Photos & negatives - Synanon v. Bernstein trial exhibits - corresponds to exhibits #475 - 477 through CED early negs, D - F. (Box 506)
  - CED early negs, I - J through Betty - CED negatives - early strips. (Box 507)
- Scrapbooks
  - Miscellaneous., 2 items [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 456)
  - Miscellaneous., 7 items [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 457)
  - Miscellaneous., 3 items [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 458)
  - Miscellaneous., 3 items [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 459)
  - Miscellaneous., 3 items & loose material [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 460)
  - Miscellaneous., 2 items [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 461)
  - Miscellaneous., 2 items [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 462)
  - Miscellaneous., 1 item [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 463)
  - Miscellaneous., 2 items [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 464)
  - Miscellaneous., 2 items [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 465)
  - Miscellaneous., 3 items [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 466)
  - Home Place family The history of women in the trades in Synanon, 1979 1958-1981.; 4 items [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 515)
  - Newspapers clippings., 1 item [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 516)
  - [Untitled]., 1 item [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 517)
  - CED's Synanon v. the Examiner scrapbook., 1 item [OVERSIZE BOX]. (Box 518)
- Slides
  - 54 through 58. (Box 320)
  - CED and others through CED portraits - CED and Betty. (Box 546)
- Subject Files
  - Academy sheet through Addiction, 1976. (Box 58)
  - Addiction (no dates) through ADGAP catalogues, 1978-1979. (Box 60)
  - ADGAP catalogues through Art show - Houston -, 1982 September 1983. (Box 61)
  - Art show - Home Place-1988 through MD - bald head day. (Box 62)
  - Baseball cards: CED, Betty & Ginny through Bette Beatty - as the club changes. (Box 63)
  - The cube: by department through Joel Kibbee's papers on the Synanon college -, 1973. (Box 64)
  - Ecology through Ralph Emerson: letter. (Box 65)
  - Fairs: through Financial report:, 1959-1968 1966. (Box 66)